<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Random Thoughts</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/rituparna-panda.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>What agile means to me</title><link href="/what-agile-means-to-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rituparna Panda</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-03:what-agile-means-to-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We all have studied about various project development methodologies in school.
Waterfall was one of the primary and prefered development methodology at that
time and was purely used by almost all the companies. Now a days Agile has
replaced all the old development life cycles and companies prefer agile over
waterfall. I have worked with both kinds of projects and personally I would
prefer agile project development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile is my prefered project development because the agile team focuses on
getting the minimum viable product (MVP) out first. Over the time the
product becomes stable with continuous end to end testing with end users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have few pros and cons listed down about agile development (these points may
not be true in every cases, the pros and cons is entirely based on my
experience with project development) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pros"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pros :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project development runs in warp speed : agile development is usually
fast because team focus on small user stories and complete it in one or
two sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need of understanding complex business process in one go : every
business have same goal (ie. being best at what they do) but works on
different principles. It is not easy for development team to understand
the entire process all in one and find a solution. Agile makes it easier
for team members to focus into one small segments at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer works closely with development team and the feedback and
suggestion loop becomes faster and continuous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cons"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cons :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the developers in the team are not aware of end goal of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The solution given to the customers is a copy of their requirement, which
is sometimes not the right solution to their problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="agile"></category></entry><entry><title>First NCR Pyladies Meetup</title><link href="/first-ncr-pyladies-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rituparna Panda</name></author><id>tag:,2014-06-27:first-ncr-pyladies-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was following Pyladies from quite a long time, and I was keen to start the
chapter here in India. Finally we could start one on our own. I am so
excited to announce that on June 14th, 2014 - 4 women (out of them 3 were
python developers) finally met for the first time at Noida for Pyladies Meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yay we made it&lt;/em&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="images/pyladies.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our first Meetup, we discussed about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each others interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up a new project and Github repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction of virtual environment and Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And agenda for next Meetup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very exciting, meeting and talking about our challenges and issues.
I called some of my male colleagues to help us and they were very positive
and enthusiastic while helping us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We planned to meet every month atleast once and learn coding together. If
anyone is interested, then please follow us on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/PyladiesIndia/"&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt;
and know more about our upcoming meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="meetup"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rituparna Panda</name></author><id>tag:,2014-06-01:hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first pelican blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>